Blanca Mendizabal Perello

Full-stack software developer recently graduated from Makers Academy, Europe's leading web development bootcamp. I'm looking for a junior developer position in a company where I can make an impact and also grow professionally.

Blog I GitHub I LinkedIn I Twitter

Skills

Project Management

I've shown strong ability breaking projects into smaller tasks while working atLittle Bee Community. I managed a project in Africa, creating a three-year timeline that included monthly and weekly tasks, cost tracking, and list of suppliers. This structured workflow made it easier to deliver the project on time and on budget.

Adaptability

For the last five years I have been experiencing big changes in my life, and I managed to successfully overcome them by focusing on my strengths and abilities. My last challenge, a career change, started one year ago when I began learning HTML, CSS and JavaScript by myself. I then decided to join Makers Academy, a 12-week bootcamp where I learnt Ruby, Rails, Node, and React, to name a few technologies. It has been an amazing and satisfying journey!

Communication and Collaboration

My colleagues at Makers highlight my empathy, patience, and ability to explain concepts clearly as my main skills. For example, on one specially challenging week I noticed that my colleague was struggling with understanding how a Node app works. I helped her analyse the project's structure and data flow. By the end of the day we managed to have a server up and running!

Design and User Experience

I'm passionate about crafting attractive and user-friendly interfaces for every project I work on. I have taught myself CSS, Bootstrap, Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator. I have used these skills to create appealing and usable apps in personal projects, and marketing materials for Little Bee Community and Battle McCarthy.

Projects

Name	Description	Technologies	Timeframe
Flashcards Client	Client side of a single-page app	React, React Toolbox	Ongoing
Flashcards Server	Server side of a single-page app	Ruby on Rails	Ongoing
CSS playground	Live-editing HTML and CSS tool	JavaScript, React, Jest	10 days
StoryApp	JavaScript single-page application	JavaScript, jQuery, Jasmine, HTML, CSS	5 days

Experience

Sustainability Consultant at Little Bee Community (London, UK) Oct 2013 - Aug 2016

Led a wide range of projects locally and abroad, ensuring goals were met on time and on budget. Created internal databases of agricultural techniques and best practices, and funding opportunities for a wide range of projects. I supported and managed volunteers and other team members.

Agricultural Engineer at Battle McCarthy (London, UK) Jan 2013 - Oct 2013

Responsible for urban agriculture R&D. I worked with five other people, developing agricultural strategies to maximise food production inside buildings using hydroponic systems.

Environmental Engineer at Aqualogy (AGBAR group) (Madrid, Spain) Sep 2011 – Sep 2012

Responsible for conducting compliance checks for the purpose of enforcing Spanish and European laws regarding water treatment. I also designed a working methodology for the analysis of biological quality parameters of Spanish rivers.

Guest Speaker at Technical University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain) Mar 2007 - Jul 2008

Participated as a guest speaker at the IV World Congress of Agricultural Engineers, presenting my final year project *'Iberian Pig Value Chain Analysis''*.

Intern (Food Sector) at Technical University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain) 2006 - 2008

Worked at the Agricultural Economy department analysing the value chain of various food products, and at the Agri-Food Industry department carrying out quality control procedures in the bread industry.

Education

Onsite Software Development Bootcamp at Makers Academy (London, UK) Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

Highly-selective 12-week full-time program (and 4-week pre-course), emphasising:

- · Front-end development
- · Back-end development
- · Pair-programming
- Test-driven development
- · Object-oriented design
- Agile methodologies

M.Sc. Environmental Engineering and Managementat EOI Business School (Madrid, Spain) 2010 -- 2011

Master thesis "Development of an Environmental Management System under the European EMAS Regulation".

M.Sc Agricultural Engineering at Technical University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain) 2000 – 2008

My final year project, "Iberian Pig Value Chain Analysis", received an outstanding qualification.

Other information

- Email: blanca.mendizabal.perello@gmail.com
- English (professional working proficiency).
- · Spanish (native).
- I love making my own bread, and photography.